Guide to the Ira L. Wiggins Papers SC0177
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ira L. Wiggins Papers
1926-1985
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wiggins, Ira L. (Ira Loren)
SC0177
8 Linear Feet
Common Abbreviations
Missing Title
A.I.N.A.- Arctic Institute of North America
A.S.P.T.- American Society of Plant Taxonomists
A.I.B.S.- American Institute of Biological Sciences
B.S.F.- Belvedere Scientific Fund
RELATED COLLECTIONS
SC0022 - Douglas H. Campbell Papers
Scope and Content
This collection covers the period 1928-65 and consists mainly of professional correspondence. Wiggins maintained long-term contact with a number of prominent botanists and participated in many professional exchanges of information and specimens, often dealing with the identification of certain flora. His field trips are described in great detail in this correspondence as well as in the various reports he wrote. There is a good amount of correspondence on his work with the Belvedere Scientific Fund in Baja California, and a fair amount of Stanford University correspondence relating to his administrative duties over the years. There are also files relating to Wiggins' duties with the American Fern Society and the Arctic Institute of North America. These files do not contain any of Prof. Wiggins' papers dealing with his research at Point Barrow, Alaska for the U.S. Government (Summer 1950- Sept. 1953 and Mar.-Oct. 1956). Field notebooks are also not included in the collection.
Additional papers were received in 1983 and 1986, largely consisting of correspondence and articles, 1926 to 1985. Of note are papers relating to Wiggin's work in Ecuador, 1944; notes from field trips to the Sonoran desert, 1926-37; typescripts of several articles; and collected materials and drafts of biographies on A. W. C. T. Herre, Gilbert M. Smith, and Carl B. Wolf.
Major correspondents include Wendell Holmes Camp and B.A. Krukoff (New York Botanical Garden), J.Pinckney Hester (Boyce Thompson Arboretum), Maximino Martinez (Sociedad Botanica de México), Wm. R. Maxon (U.S. National Museum), Reed C. Rollins (Gray Herbarium, Harvard and U.S. Bureau of Plant Industry), Forrest Shreve (Carnegie Institute Division of Plant Biology, Desert Investigations), William Steere (Department of Botany, University of Michigan and Editor, American Journal of Botany), Albert M.Vollmer, M.D. (accompanied Wiggins on field trips), William A. Weber (Univesity of Colorado), and Carol H. Woodward (New York Botanical Garden and editor for several of Wiggins' articles).
Professor Wiggins grouped his correspondence alphabetically within certain time periods. Certain major correspondents have their own folders, but it is wise to check the general correspondence files as well. The accessions received in 1983 and 1986 were combined and processed as "additional papers." As far as possible original folder labels were retained; the folders were then arranged alphabetically. Where appropriate, correspondence from the general correspondence folders was removed and given separate folders.
Biography
Ira Loren Wiggins, Emeritus Professor of Biology, former Curator of the Dudley Herbarium and Director of the Natural History Museum, was born on January 1, 1899. He received his A.B. degree from Occidental College in 1922, his A.M. from Stanford in 1925, and His Ph.D. in botany from Stanford in 1930. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1929 and became Emeritus Professor of Biology in 1964.
Professor Wiggins was active in a number of organizations in his field. He served as President of the American Fern Society, the California Botanical Society, the California Academy of Sciences, and the American Society of Plant Taxonomists. He was a member of the Board of Governors of the Arctic Society of America and Editor of the American Fern Journal. He served as Scientific Director of the Arctic Research Laboratory at Point Barrow, Alaska and conducted botanical field research in Baja California under the auspices of the Belvedere Scientific Fund. His publications include over 100 papers dealing with systematic botany and plant ecology. His book A Flora of the Alaskan Arctic Slope, written in conjunction with John Hunter Thomas, Asst. Curator of the Dudley Herbarium and lecturer in biology at Stanford, was published by the University of Toronto Press in 1962.
Provenance
Gift of Ira L. Wiggins
Access Restrictions
The materials are open for research use.
Baja California (Mexico: Peninsula); Zoology -- Arctic regions; Botany -- Arctic regions.; Biology -- Fieldwork.; Wiggins, Ira L. (Ira Loren); Wiggins, Ira L. (Ira Loren); Camp, W. H. (Wendell Holmes); Stanford University. Natural History Museum; Hester, J. Pinckney.; Arctic Institute of North America.; Stanford University. Department of Biology -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Maxon, William R. (William Ralph); Rollins, Reed C. (Reed Clark); Dudley Herbarium; Krukoff, B. A.; Martinez, Maximino.; Vollmer, Albert M.; Shreve, Forrest.; Steere, William Campbell,; Belvedere Scientific Fund.; Woodward, Carol H.
- General Files
  - Acknowledgements, 1955-62 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address and Appointment Changes, 1958-62 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alaskan Science Conference, Nov 9-11, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Fern Society, Correll, Donovan S., Correspondence, 1964-5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Fern Society, Correspondence, Nov-Dec 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Fern Society, Correspondence, Jan-May 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Fern Society, Correspondence, Jun-Oct 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Fern Society, Membership Lists, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Fern Society, Inc., Orders of Council, (also list of orders, 1954-64 1914-1941) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Fern Society, Fern Journal Guides, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Fern Society, Fern Journal Reprinting, 1963-4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Fern Society, Spore Exchange, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Institute for Biological Sciences (A.I.B.S.) Correspondence, 1957-64 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A.I.B.S. Emergency Meeting, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A.I.B.S. Meetings, 1962-3 and undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Society of Plant Taxonomists (ASPT), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    (includes Wiggins' Presidential Report).
  - Arctic Institute of North America (AINA), Correspondence, Jan-May 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - AINA, Correspondence, 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - AINA, Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AINA, Correspondence, 1962-65 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - AINA, Grant in Aid, 1954, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AINA, Publications Committee (Including Minutes), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Arctic Research Laboratory, Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Baja Field Workers. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Belvedere Scientific Fund, Beatty, Wm. Proposal for Mineral Resource Data Project, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Belvedere Scientific Fund, Correspondence, 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Belvedere Scientific Fund (BSF), Correspondence., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Belvedere Scientific Fund (BSF), Correspondence, Jan-May 19 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - BSF, Correspondence, Jun-Dec 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - BSF, Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - BSF, Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - BSF, Insular Floras of Baja California, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - BSF, List of Collections, Baja California Field Work, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - BSF, Maps of Baja California, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - BSF, Miscellaneous, 1958-63 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - BSF, Officials and Influential People in Baja and M.D.F., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - BSF, Permits, 1959-63 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - BSF, Progress Reports (Quarterly), 1961-4 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - BSF, Reference Articles 1948, 1957 and undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - BSF, Register of Field Trips, 1959-62 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - BSF, Sales Receipts, Oct-Dec 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - BSF, Stebbings, James, 1960-61 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - BSF, Tape Transcriptions, trips., 1959,1960, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - BSF, Travellall, 1959-65 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - BSF, Trip Reports Log, Oct-Dec, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - BSF, Trip Reports and Logs, 1960-64 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1936-44 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, A-K., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, L-Z., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, A-P., 1934-40 except Jun-Nov 1937 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, T-Z., 1934-40 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Bailey Hortorium, Cornell University, 1934-39 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Baxter, E.M. (The Cactus and Succulent Society of America)., 1934-39 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Spoehr, H.A. (Division of Plant Biology, Carnegie Institution of Washington)., 1934-39 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Shreve, Forrest (Desert Laboratory of Plant Biology, Carnegie Institution of Washington)., 1933-40 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Shreve, Forrest., 1i33-40 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Whitehead, Jack (Boyce Thompson Southwestern Arboretum)., 1934-40 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Wolf, Carl B. (Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden)., 1936-39 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, (Sabbatical)., Jun-Nov 1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, C., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, C., 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, D-E., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, F-G., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, H., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, H., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, I-J., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, K., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, L., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, M., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, M., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, N-P., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, R., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, T-Whitehead., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Weatherby- Z., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, S., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, S., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, S., 1940-Aug 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, S., 1951-1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, S., 1951-58 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Kellogg, Remington (U.S. National Museum, Smithsonian Institution)., 1955-57 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - A Flora of the Alaskan Arctic Slope, Correspondence, 1961-62 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - A Flora of the Alaskan Arctic Slope, Reviews, 1962-64 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts (Carbons), 1951 and undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Natural History Museum-Statement of Funds, 1942-44 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Final Report- Contract Nonr 248(04). (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Systematic and Cyto-Taxonomic Investigation of the Vascular Plants in the U.S. Naval Petroleum Reserve No. 4.
    Ira Wiggins, Research Contract Director, 31 March 1953 Office of Naval Research.
  - Papers: Notes on Certain Plants of Lower California and Medicinal Uses of Certain Mexican Plants., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Zoological Garden, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Plants of San Diego County, List of. Prepared by the Brandegees, 1902-3 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Shreve, Forrest. Biographical and Bibliographical Information, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Society for the Study of Speciation, 1940's (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Biology Department (Stanford), 1950-51 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Business Office (Stanford), 1950 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University-Dudley Herbarium, Railway Express Agency, Receipts for Specimens Sent, 1941-43 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University- General Correspondence, Includes lists of Wiggins' Publications, 1928-39 1935-39 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University-General Correspondence, 1940-45 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Stanford University-General Correspondence, 1940-45 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University- General Correspondence, 1940-45 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University, General Correspondence, 1951-58 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University, Personnel, non-academic. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University President's Office, Correspondence, 1942-56 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Stanford University President's Office, Correspondence, 1934-Jun 1942 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, 1933-35 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, Correspondence, 1941-45 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, Symposium, Dec-40 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Press, 1943-58 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Steere, William, Correspondence, 1949-58 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - President's Office: Appointments for Geo. Vanderbilt Fund (GVF), 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Presidents Office Appointments for Natural History Museum, 1951-1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University President's Office, President's Report, 1958-59 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University Provost's Office, 1953-61 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University, Public Exercises (Committee on), 1947-60 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tidelands Survey Article, The Relation of Salt Marsh Plants To Tide Levels Along the California Coast and Their Significance in Certain Litigation. n.d. (I. Wiggins). Includes draft. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Tidelands Survey, Correspondence and miscellaneous material, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tidelands Survey, Dunbarton Tides, 1936-37 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Tidelands Survey, Elevations of vegetation near Ford plant, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Tidelands Survey, Photographs and Negatives, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Tidelands Survey, Photographs and Negatives, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tidelands Survey, Photographs and Negatives, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Tidelands Survey, Photostats of Reprints on Salt Marsh Studies, requested, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Vollmer, Albert M., 1934-55 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Western Museums Conference, 1940-42 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, 1933-1935 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Western Society of Naturalists, Symposium - Includes Wiggins paper, "Training for Research and Instruction in the Biological Sciences" (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Western Society of Naturalists - Wiggins paper on Galapagos (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - A correspondence., 1940-69 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1942-45 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1959-65 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Berkeley meeting, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1942-44 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - American Fern Society, 1941-44 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - American Fern Society, 1963-65 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - American Society of Plant Taxonomists, 1943, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Artic Research Lab, 1953-54 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Atkinson, Lenette, 1964-66 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, December 1960 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - B correspondence, 1936-45, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Babcock, E. B., 1941-45 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Bailey, I. W., 1942-45 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Belvedere Scientific Fund, 1960-77 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Benson, Lyman D., 1940-44 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Biological Abstracts: correspondence and text (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bonestell Company, correspondence, 1942-45 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Botanical Society of America, 1940-44 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - C correspondence, 1965-74 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - California Botanical Society, 1965-73 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - California State College at Fullerton, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1931-32 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, last name undecipherable or missing (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - D - H correspondence, 1943-77 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Darwin Foundation, 1968-75 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Dorst, Jean, 1966-68, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Drawings (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ecuador trip, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ecuador trip, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ecuador trip, FEA correspondence, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Ecuador trip, correspondence, 1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ecuador trip, financial records (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Ecuador trip, notes, lab analysis reports (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Ecuador trip, misc. correspondence and memos, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ecuador trip, field notes (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Ecuador trip, preliminary drafts of reports (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Emory, David L., 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Flora of the Galapagos, ad for (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Flora of the Galapagos, correspondence re, 1971-76 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Focht, David, 1966-68 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Galapago - articles (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Galapagos correspondence, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Galapagos - grant, 1966-68 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Galapagos Science Conference, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Gilbreath, Robert, "First Find the Flower,", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hanna, G. Dallas (Artic Research Lab), 1955-57 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hauke, Richard L., 1964-65 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Herre, A. W. C. T, bibliography (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Herre, A. W. C. T, "Notes on My Life" (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Herre, A. W. C. T, correspondence, 1959-62 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Howell, J. T. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Huttleston, D. G., 1963-65 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - I - L correspondence, 1943-74 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jarret, Frances M., 1968-69 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Knobloch, Irving, 1965-66 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Lellinger, David, 1965-74 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - List of determinations (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Loans (herbarium specimens) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - M correspondence, 1944-74 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - McGinnies, W. G., 1972-81 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Morton, C. V., 1950-65 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - N correspondence, 1951-72 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - National Medal of Science (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation, 1965-75 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Nature Conservancy, "Natural Areas Inventory of California, Vegetation Types, Santa Barbara, November 25, 1957" (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - New York Botanical Garden, 1951-71 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notes on the natural history of Yucca Volida [author not specified] (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - O correspondence, 1951-77 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Orr, Robert T., 1965-74 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ownbey, Gerald B., 1955-57 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Pa - Pe correspondence, 1961-74 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ph - Po correspondence, 1962-83 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pr - Py correspondence, 1967-76 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Pacific Science Association (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Persson, Herman, 1961-69 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Peterson, Roger (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Plattner, Phyllis - correspondence and descriptions of plants to be drawn (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Porsild, A. E., 1957-69 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Porter, Duncan, 1959-73 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Poulter, Thomas C., 1961-67 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Project Skijump, Woods Hole Oceaneographic Institute, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Q correspondence, 1954-71 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Ra - Rh correspondence, 1960-75 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Ri - Ro correspondence, 1959-85 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Ru - Ry correspondence, 1962-74 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Raup, Hugh M., 1963-82 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Raven, Peter H., 1962-73 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Requests for information (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Reveal, James L., 1972-75 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Rick, Charles M., 1968-70 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Rockefeller, Mrs. David (National Comm. For the Wildflowers), 1960-73 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Rollins, Reed C., 1951-74 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Rossbach, George B., 1955-60 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Rudd, Velva E., 1973-75 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Rzedowski, J., 1960-73 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Sa - Se correspondence, 1959-75 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Sh - Sl correspondence, 1962-72 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Sm - Sp correspondence, 1960-75 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - St - Sw correspondence, 1960-75 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Savile, D. B. O., 1960-74 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Sawyer, E. W., 1964-65 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Schrenk, W. Jurgen, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Senate Bill 1991 (re national tropical botanical garden), 1964 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Sharp, Aaron J., 1963-71 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Shreve's original photographs of desert plants, correspondence re, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Skvortzov, A. K., 1964-67 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Smith, C. P., estate of, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Clyde, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Gilbert M., biographical sketch of (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Gilbert M. (Memorial Resolution) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Smith, Lyman B., 1960-62 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Snow, David W., 1968-75 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Snyder, John O., memorial resolution (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Solbrig, Otto T., 1961-75 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Sonora Field Trip, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Sonoran Desert (notes, reports, plant lists, photographs, correspondence), 1926-37 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Stafleu, F. A., 1965-68 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - St. John, Harold, 1951-63 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - S.U. Dudley Herbarium, photocopies of specimens (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - S.U. General Secretary, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - S.U. miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - S.U. Natural History Museum, 1942-54 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - S.U. Natural History Museum, 1957-74 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - S.U. Natural History Museum, publications (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - S.U. President's office, 1946-72 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - S.U. Press, 1959-72, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - S.U. Registrar's Office (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - S.U. Safety Director (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - S.U. School of Biological Sciences (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - S.U. student protests [orig. labelled "radicals"] (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Stebbins, G. L., Jr., 1954 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Steere, W. C., 1959-74 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Stern, William L., 1962-67 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Storey, Margaret H., 1960-61 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Strother, John L., (includes typescript of Wiggins' "Ranunculus Flagelliformis Smith Discoverd in the Galapagos Islands"), 1970-74 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Summer Institute in Desert Biology (Tempe, AZ), 1961-68 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Swallen, Jason R., 1955-63 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Symposium on the Biology of the California Channel Islands, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Ta - Ti correspondence, 1960-71 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - To - Tu correspondence, 1960-72 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Tedrow, J.C.F., 1961-63 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Thomas, John, 1961-75 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Thompson, J. W., 1963 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Thorne, Robert F., 1967-74 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Tryon, Rolla M., and Alice Tryon, 1961-72, 1963-67 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Tucker, J. M., 1961-70 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Turner, B.L., 1960-74 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Turner, George C., 1966 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Turner, Raymond M., 1960-75 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - U correspondence, 1951-70 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - United States Dept. of Agriculture (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Univ. of Alaska Museum - report, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Univ. of California, extension lectures, correspondence re, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Univ. of California Press, correpondence and bills, 1951-1970 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Univ. of Florida, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Univ. of Michigan, Committee on a Proposed Center for Tropical Studies, progress report, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Univ. of Michigan, summer session, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - V correspondence, 1949-73 (Box 15, Folder 25)